这是什么警报
What's the emergency?
淡紫色警报
It's mauve.
淡紫色
Mauve?
全宇宙通用的示警色
Universally recognised colour for danger.
怎么不是红色警报
What happened to red?
只有人类用红色
That's just humans.
按其他种族的标准 红色太招摇了
By everyone else's standards, red's camp.
会引发许多误解
Oh, the misunderstandings!
跳来跳去闪烁个不停
All those red alerts, all that dancing!
它的飞行系统很基础
It's got very basic fly computer
我已经黑进去了 让它引导着塔迪斯
I've hacked in, slaved the TARDIS.
它飞到哪 我们就跟到哪儿
Wherever it goes, we go!
那样安全吗
And that's safe is it?
绝对安全
Totally.
好吧 相对安全 我应该说"相对"
OK, reasonably. Should have said "reasonably" there.
不 它在跨跃时间轨道
No! It's jumping time tracks,
我们要跟丢了
getting away from us!
那到底是什么东西啊
What exactly is this thing?
不知道
No idea.
那我们追它做什么
Then why are we chasing it?
因为它是淡紫色的危险
It's mauve and dangerous,
而且再过30秒就要撞到伦敦市中心了
and about 30 seconds from the centre of London.
神秘博士第一季第九集
虚无男孩
编剧 史蒂文·莫法特
你知道我们在不撞上地球的情况下
D'you know how long you can knock around space
能在宇宙中遨游多久吗
without happening to bump into Earth?
五天 或者是储备的牛奶喝完了
Five days? Or is that just when we're out of milk?
宇宙这么大 种族这么多
All the species in all the universe,
为什么非得是牛不可呢
and it has to come out of a cow!
坠落地点肯定不远
Must've come down somewhere quite close,
应该在一英里之内吧
within a mile anyway.
时间应该也不会超过几个星期
And it can't have been more than a few week ago.
顶多一个月
Maybe a month.
一个月 我们就跟在它后面
A month? We were right behind it.
它跨时间轨道了 到处跳呢
It was jumping time tracks. It's all over the place.
难免会有少许偏差 要不你来驾驶
We're bound to be a little bit out. Do you wanna drive?
好吧 少许是多少
Yeah. How much is a little?
一点点
A bit.
真的是一点点吗
Is that exactly a bit?
大概吧
Ish.
那你打算怎么找
What's the plan, then?
你不用扫描一下外星科技吗
You gonna do a scan for alien tech or something?
洛斯 这东西掉在伦敦城里肯定动静很大
Rose, it hit the middle of London with a very loud bang.
我打听一下就行了
I'm gonna ask.
约翰·史密斯博士 小行星事务部
"Dr John Smith, Ministry of Asteroids."
这是通灵纸片 它会让你…
It's psychic paper, it tells you what...
看到你想让我看到的东西 我记得
Whatever you want it to tell me, I remember.
抱歉
Sorry.
光问的话 会不会不够史波克
Not very Spock, is it, just asking?
门 音乐 人声 你觉得需要吗
Door, music, people, what do you think?
我看你应该扫描一下外星科技
I think you should do a scan for alien tech.
让我看看炫酷的科技 你会死吗
Gimme some Spock for once! Would it kill ya?
你这身衣服不太合适吧
You sure about that T-shirt?
说不准 先穿出去转转再说
Too early to say. I'm taking it out for a spin.
妈咪
Mummy!
你来不来 应该用不了多久
Come on, if you're coming! It won't take a minute.
妈咪
Mum-my!
博士 博士 上面有个小孩
Doctor? Doctor, there's a kid up there!
♪没有谁能♪
♪For nobody else♪
♪能撩动我心弦♪
♪Gave me the thrill♪
♪你伤我千遍 我却爱你依旧♪
♪With all your faults I love you still♪
♪只有你一个♪
♪It had to be you♪
♪只有完美的你♪
♪Wonderful you♪
你还好吗
Are you all right up there?
妈咪
Mum-my!
♪别无他人♪
♪It had to be you♪
抱歉抱歉 大家能听我说句话吗
Excuse me! Excuse me, could I have everybody's attention?
就问一句话 很快就好
Just for a mo. Be very quick.
你们好啊
Hello!
这问题听起来可能有点蠢
Might seem like a stupid question,
最近有没有什么东西从天上掉下来
but has anything fallen from the sky recently?
妈咪
Mummy!
坚持住 别乱动
OK, hang on, don't move!
抱歉 我说了什么好笑的话了吗
Sorry, have I said something funny?
我正在找这么一个东西
It's just there's this thing I need to find.
应该是几天前从天上掉下来的
Would've fallen from the sky a couple of days ago.
应该就落在这一带
Would've landed quite near here...
动静非常…
with a very loud...
大家动作快 去防空洞
Quickly as you can, down to the shelters.
希特勒不会给你预警
…大
bang.
妈咪
Mummy?
气球
Balloon!
博士
Doctor!
好吧 也许真穿错衣服了
OK, maybe not this T-shirt.
洛斯
Rose?
你知道吗 总有一天…
You know, one day...
总有一天 也许
just one day, maybe,
我会遇到一个
I'm gonna meet somebody
听得懂"不要乱跑"的人
who gets the whole "Don't wander off" thing.
在电话亭里旅行了900年
900 years of phone-box travel,
只有这一件事不停地出乎我意料
it's the only thing left to surprise me!
你怎么会响呢
How can you be ringing?
什么毛病 怎么还响了呢
What's that about - ringing?
电话响了我该怎么办呢
What am I supposed to do with a ringing phone?
不要接
Don't answer it.
不是打给你的
It's not for you.
你怎么知道呢
And how do you know that?
我就是知道
Cos I do.
我警告你
And I'm telling ya.
别接电话
Don't answer it.
既然你知道这么多 那你说说
If you know so much, tell me this
这电话怎么能响呢
how can it be ringing?
这又不是真正的电话
It's not even a real phone,
它又没接上电话线 它…
it's not connected, it's not...
你好
Hello?
我是博士
This is the Doctor speaking.
请问找我有什么事
How may I help you?
妈咪
Mummy?
Mummy!
你是谁
Who is this?
谁在说话
Who's speaking?
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
你是谁
Who is this?
妈咪
Mummy!
你是怎么打过来的呢
How did you ring here?
这又不是真的电话 也没接上线…
This isn't a real phone, it's not wired up to...
妈咪
Mummy?
洛斯
Rose?
洛斯 你在里面吗
Rose, are you in there?
轰炸机又来了 你听不见吗
The planes are coming. Can't you hear 'em?
进防空洞去 少废话 快进去
Into the shelter. None of your nonsense. Now move it!
快 快点 进去 动作快
Come on! Hurry up, get in there. Come on.
亚瑟 亚瑟你能不能快点
Arthur? Arthur, will you 'urry up? !
没听见防空警报吗
Didn't you hear the siren?
每次都是晚饭时间来轰炸
Middle of dinner, every night.
该死的德国佬 他们不吃晚饭的吗
Bloomin' Germans! Don't they eat?
我都能听见飞机声了
I can hear the planes.
还让不让人吃饭了
Don't you eat?
你小点声行不行 这可是空袭
Oh, keep your voice down, it's an air raid!
快进去 这可是打仗呢
Get in! Look, there's a war on.
我知道 别推我
I know there is! Don't push me.
把灯关了 所有人马上去防空洞
Get those lights out. Everyone down to the shelter.
杰克 你不去防空洞吗
Jack, you going down to the shelter?
我还必须去执行什么愚蠢的看守任务
Only I've got to go off on some damn silly guard duty.
防空气球 怎么
Barrage balloon, eh?
估计是缆绳断了 最近常有这事
Must've come loose. Happens now and then.
你们空军不是常用它做射击练习吗
Don't you RAF boys use them for target practice?
翘臀啊
Excellent bottom!
我说伙计 注意场合
I say, old man, there's a time and a place.
说真的 该下去了
Look, um, should really be off.
抱歉了哥们 我得去见个姑娘
Sorry, old man! I gotta go meet a girl.
但你也有个翘臀
But you've got an excellent bottom too!
外面有很多孩子吗
Many kids out there?
是的 小姐
Yes, Miss...
等着 我还没切好呢
Ah! Still carving.
坐好了等着
Sit and wait.
离空袭结束还远着呢
Got the whole air raid!
瞧瞧 我猜肯定是黑市搞来的
Look at that. Bet it's off the black market.
别乱说话
That's enough!
别慌 我接住你了
OK, I've got you.
谁接住我了
Who's got me?
谁接的 怎么接的
Who's got me and, you know, how?
我正在计算你的下落轨迹
I'm programming your descent pattern.
尽量别动 请不要把手脚伸出光柱
Stay still as you can, and keep your hands and feet inside the light field.
下落轨迹
Descent pattern?
对了 你能先把手机关一下吗
Oh, and can you switch off your cell phone?
说真的 我的仪器受干扰了
No, seriously. It interferes with my instruments.
真不敢相信
You know no-one ever believes that?
谢谢 好多了
Thank you, that's much better.
是啊 我关机帮了大忙呢
Oh, yeah, that's a real load off I'm that is.
德国在空袭 我却挂在半空中
I'm hanging in the sky in the middle of a German air raid,
胸前还印着英国国旗 不过没关系
with a Union Jack across my chest but, hey,
我已经把手机关机了
my mobile phone's off!
稍等片刻
Be with you in a moment.
移动通讯设备表明
The mobile communication device indicates
此生命形态来自另一个时代
non-contemporaneous life form.
她确实不是这个时代的人
She's not from around here, no.
准备好了 抓紧了
Ready for you. Hold tight!
抓什么
To what?
有道理
Fair point.
我接住你了 你没事的 没事的
I've got you. You're fine, you're just fine.
牵引光束可能会让你有点头晕
The tractor beam, it can scramble your head just a little.
你好
Hello.
抱歉 我说了两遍你好
Sorry. There was "hello" twice there.
挺傻的 但是比较彻底嘛
Dull but, you know, thorough.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
挺好的
I'm fine.
为什么这么问 你以为我会晕倒吗
Why, you expecting me to faint or something?
我看你有点晕
You look a little dizzy.
那你呢 我看都眼花缭乱了…
What about you? You're not even in focus...
肯定是从黑市上搞到的
It's got to be black market.
用配给券根本领不到这么多
You couldn't get all this on coupons.
厄尼 跟你说过多少次了
Ernie, how many times?
在这里我们是客人
We're guests in this house!
不可以对主人说三道四
We will not make comments of that kind.
罚你洗碗
Washing up!
别这样 南希
Oh, Nancy!
我以前没见过你啊
Haven't seen you at one of these before.
他告诉我的
He told me about it.
露宿街头了吗
Sleeping rough?
是的 小姐
Yes, Miss.
好吧
All right, then.
每人只准拿一片
One slice each.
每个人都给我细嚼慢咽
And I want to see everybody chewing properly.
谢谢您 小姐
Thank you, Miss.
谢谢 小姐
Thanks, Miss.
谢谢您 小姐
Thank you, Miss!
谢谢 小姐
Thanks, Miss!
没事的 大家全都坐好
It's all right, everybody stay where they are!
这里真不错 是吧 谁有盐
Good here, innit? Who's got the salt?
回到你们的座位
Back in your seats.
他不是这里的主人
He shouldn't be here either.
你们大家
So, you lot,
都是什么来路
what's the story?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你们都是流浪儿 对吧 生活艰难
You're homeless, right? Living rough?
你问这个干什么
Why do you wanna know that?
你是警察吗
Are you a copper?
当然不是了
Course I'm not a copper.
再说了 警察能拿你们怎么办
What's a copper gonna do with you lot anyway?
以挨饿的罪名逮捕你们吗
Arrest you for starving?
现在是1941年吧
I make it 1941.
你们甚至都不该在伦敦
You lot shouldn't even be in London.
应该已经撤退到了乡下才对
Should've been evacuated to the country by now.
我是被疏散了 被送到一个农场
I was evacuated. Sent me to a farm.
那你为什么回来
So why'd you come back?
那里有个人…
There was a man there...
他跟厄尼一样 辗转两家之前的事了
Yeah. Same with Ernie. Two homes ago.
闭嘴 我在街头反而还过得好些
Shut up! It's better on the streets anyway.
吃的也更好
It's better food.
是啊 南希总是给我们找到最好的食物
Yeah. Nancy always gets the best food for us.
你就是干这个的呀 南希
So that's what you do, is it, Nancy?
什么
What is?
警报一响
Soon as the sirens go,
人们都躲进防空洞
you find a big fat family meal,
你就能在别人家的桌子上
still warm on the table
找到冒着热气的一顿大餐 大功告成
with everyone down in the air raid shelter, and bingo!
伦敦城里的流浪儿都可以来饱餐一顿
Feeding frenzy for the homeless kids of London Town!
人人都饿不着
Puddings for all!
只要别被炸弹炸到就行
As long as the bombs don't get you.
有问题吗
Something wrong with that?
哪有问题呀 太妙了
Wrong with it? It's brilliant.
这要么是现实版马克思主义
I'm not sure if it's Marxism in action
要么是西区音乐剧的场景
or a West End musical.
你为什么要跟着我
Why did you follow me?
你有什么目的
What d'you want?
我就想知道一个假电话为什么会真响
I want to know how a phone that isn't a phone gets a phone call.
我觉得应该问你
You seem to be the one to ask.
我是在帮你
I did you a favour.
让你别接那个电话 仅此而已
I told you not to answer it. That's all I'm telling ya.
很好 谢谢
Great, thanks!
我还想找一个衣服上有国旗的金发姑娘
And I wanna find a blonde in a Union Jack.
我是说确有其人
I mean a specific one,
而不是早晨醒来突发奇想
I didn't just wake up this morning with a craving.
有人见过这么一个姑娘吗
Anybody seen a girl like that?
我做错什么了
What've I done wrong?
你拿了两片
You took two slices.
没见过这么个人
No blondes, no flags.
走之前还有什么想要的
Anything else before you leave?
没错 确实有 多谢你问起
Yeah, there is, actually, thanks for asking.
我在找一个东西
Something I've been looking for.
大约是一个月前从天上掉下来的
Would've fallen from the sky about a month ago,
但不是炸弹
but not a bomb.
反正不是普通炸弹
Not the usual kind, anyway.
应该没有爆炸
Wouldn't have exploded.
可能只是埋藏在地下某处
Probably would've just buried itself in the ground somewhere.
大概长得像…
And it would've looked something like...
这样
this.
妈咪 妈咪你在里面吗
Mummy? Are you in there, Mummy?
妈咪
Mummy?
谁是最后一个进来的
Who was the last one in?
他
Him.
不 他是从后门进来的
Nah, he came round the back.
谁是从前门进来的
Who came in the front?
我
Me.
你关门了没有
Did you close the door?
我…
I...
你关门了没有
Did you close the door?
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy?
妈咪
Mum-my!
这是怎么回事
What's this then?
天这么冷 一个孩子留在外面肯定不好受
Never easy being the only child left out in the cold, you know.
我以为你知道
I suppose you'd know!
我还真知道
I do actually, yes.
那其实不是个孩子
It's not exactly a child.
妈咪
Mum-my!
大家快出去
Right, everybody out.
躲到后花园另一头的篱笆下面
Across the back garden, under the fence.
快点 动起来
Now! Go! Move!
快点 走了
Come on!
走吧 亲爱的 咱们得走了
Come on, baby, we've got to go.
把这当成追逐游戏就好
It's just like a game, just like chasing.
拿着你的衣服 去吧
Take your coat, go on.
快去
Go!
妈咪 妈咪 请让我进来 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy? Please let me in, Mummy.
请让我进来 妈咪
Please let me in, Mummy.
你还好吗
You all right?
请让我进来
Please let me in.
千万别让他碰到你
You mustn't let him touch ya.
碰到的话会怎样
What happens if he touches me?
你会变得和他一样
He'll make you like him!
他长什么样
And what's he like?
我得走了
I've gotta go.
南希 他长什么样
Nancy, what's he like.
他是空心的
He's empty.
是他打的
It's him.
他能让电话响起来
He can make phones ring. He can.
警亭里的那个电话就是他打的
Just like with that police box you saw!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my Mummy?
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy?
请让我进去 妈咪
Please let me in, Mummy.
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mum-my! Mum-my! Mum-my!
你爱走不走
You stay here if you want to!
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mum-my! Mum-my! Mum-my!
妈咪
Mummy?
让我进去吧 求你了 妈咪
Let me in, please, Mummy.
请让我进去
Please let me in!
你妈妈不在这里
Your mummy isn't here.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
这里没有妈咪
No mummies here.
没有别人 只有我们小鸡
Nobody here but us chickens...
好吧 就我一只小鸡
Well, this chicken.
我好害怕
I'm scared.
为什么别的孩子都怕你
Why are those other children frightened of you?
请让我进去 妈咪 我害怕炸弹
Please let me in, Mummy. I'm scared of the bombs.
好吧
OK.
我现在要开门了
I'm opening the door now.
现在好点了吗
Better now?
这儿有灯吗
You got lights in here?
你好
Hello.
别又来一遍
Let's not start that again.
好吧
OK.
那么 你的真实身份是什么
So, um, who are you supposed to be, then?
杰克·哈克尼斯上校 133中队
Captain Jack Harkness, 133 Squadron,
皇家空军美国志愿兵
Royal Air Force, American volunteer.
骗人 这是通灵纸片
Liar. This is psychic paper,
你想让我知道什么 它就显示什么
it tells me whatever you want it to tell me.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
两个原因
Two things.
首先 我有个朋友经常用这个
One, I have a friend that uses this all the time,
其次 你刚才递过来的纸上
and, two, you just handed me a piece of paper
写着你单身而且经常健身
telling me you're single and you workout.
这东西容易玩脱
Tricky thing, psychic paper.
是啊
Yeah.
递给别人的时候千万别走神
Can't let your mind wander when you're handing it over.
你似乎有个叫米奇·史密斯的男友
Oh, you sort of have a boyfriend called Mickey Smith,
不过你觉得自己无牵无挂
but you consider yourself to be footloose and fancy free.
什么
What?
事实上你用的词是 "单身"
Actually the word you use is "available".
不可能
No way!
又出现一个词 "真的"
And another one, "very".
咱们能不能把通灵纸片放下再说话
Shall we try and get along without the psychic papers?
那样会好一点
That would be better, wouldn't it?
飞船挺不错的
Nice spaceship.
我的座驾
Gets me around.
非常的…
Very...
史波克
Spock.
谁
Who?
我猜你不是本地人吧
Guessing you're not a local boy, then?
手机 液晶手表
A cell phone, a liquid-crystal watch and
至少二十年后才会出现的纤维制品
fabrics that won't be around for at least another two decades.
我猜你也不是本地姑娘吧
Guessing you're not a local girl.
猜对了
Guessing right.
被绳子擦破手了
Burn your hands on the rope?
是的
Yeah.
我们停在半空中
We're parked in mid-air!
下面的人看不到我们吗
Can't anyone down there see us?
看不到
No.
能给我看一下你的手吗
Can I have a look at your hands for a moment?
为什么
Why?
请让我看下
Please.
不用再演戏了
You can stop acting now.
你是干什么的我一清二楚
I know exactly who you are.
时间特工我隔着一英里都能认出来
I can spot a Time Agent a mile away.
时间特工
A Time Agent?
早就等着你们出现了
Mmm, I've been expecting one of you guys to show up.
不过没想到是搭防空气球来的
Though not, I must say, by barrage balloon!
你经常这样子旅行吗
You often travel that way?
有时会有点神魂颠倒
Sometimes I get swept off my feet.
因为气球
B-By balloons!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
尽量不要动
Try to keep still.
纳米基因体
Nanogenes.
亚原子机器人
Subatomic robots.
这里到处都是
And here is full of them.
它们刚修复了你的三层皮肤
They just repaired three layers of your skin.
替我谢谢它们
Oh! Well, tell 'em, thanks.
可以开始谈正事了吧
Shall we get down to business?
什么正事
Business?
到阳台上喝一杯吧
Shall we have a drink on the balcony?
把杯子拿上来
Bring up the glasses.
我脚下肯定不是空的
I know I'm standing on something...
好吧 你有一架隐形飞船
OK, you have an invisible space ship.
是啊
Yeah.
为什么跟大本钟拴在了一起
Tethered up to Big Ben for some reason.
飞船动态伪装第一原则
First rule of active camouflage:
停在一个不容易忘记的地方
park somewhere you'll remember.
你是怎么跟过来的
How'd you follow me here?
我很擅长跟踪 我鼻子很灵的
I'm good at following, mate. Got the nose for it!
一般人可没办法悄无声息的跟着我
People can't usually follow me if I don't want them to.
我的鼻子有超能力
My nose has special powers.
是吗 怪不得它这么…
Yeah? Is that why it's so...
怎么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing!
你的耳朵是不是也有超能力
Do your ears have special powers too?
你想说什么
What are you trying to say?
晚安 先生
Good night, Mister.
南希 有东西追着你和其他孩子
Nancy... There's something chasing you and the other kids.
看起来像个小男孩 其实不是
It looks like a boy and it isn't a boy.
是一个月前开始出现的 对吧
And it started about a month ago. Right?
我在找的那个东西
The thing I'm looking for...
也是一个月前从天上掉下来的
the thing that fell from the sky, that's when it landed.
你知道我在说什么 对吗
And you know what I'm talking about, don't you?
有一个长得像炸弹 但不是炸弹的东西
There was a bomb.A bomb that wasn't a bomb.
落在了莱姆豪斯区格林火车站的另一头
Fell the other end of Limehouse Green Station.
带我过去
Take me there.
那里有士兵把守 还有铁丝网围着
Soldiers guarding it. Barbed wire.
你过不去的
You'd never get through.
让我试试嘛
Try me!
你真的想知道那里的情况吗
You sure you want to know what's going on in there?
真的很想
I really wanna know.
那你得先去和那个人谈一谈
Then there's someone you need to talk to first.
那人是谁呢
And who might that be?
博士
The doctor.
时间不早了 我真的得回去了
It's getting late. I should really be getting back.
我们在谈正事呢
We're discussing business.
什么正事 明明是在喝香槟
This isn't business, this is champagne.
我尽量不在头脑清醒的时候谈正事
I try never to discuss business with a clear head.
你是一个人旅行吗
Are you travelling alone?
你是否有权跟我谈判
Are you authorised to negotiate with me?
我们谈什么
What would we be negotiating?
我有东西要给时间特工
I have something for the Time Agency.
一些他们想买的东西
Something they'd like to buy.
你有权和我交易吗
Are you empowered to make payment?
这个 我应该先告诉我的…
Well, I, I should talk to my... companion.
同伴
companion.
Companion?
我真的该马上回去找他了
I should really be getting back to him.
他
Him?
现在几点了
Do you have the time?
这招挺炫的
OK, that was flash!
确实挺炫酷的
That was on the flash side.
当你说你有个"同伴"时
So, when you say your "companion",
我该有多么失望呢
just how disappointed should I be?
我们现在身处半空中
OK. We're standing in mid-air,
站在一架飞船上 德军还在空袭
on a spaceship, during a German air raid.
这个时候向我献殷勤真的合适吗
Do you really think now is a good time to be coming on to me?
好像不太合适
Perhaps not.
我就说说而已
Well, it was just a suggestion.
你喜欢格伦·米勒吗
Do you like Glenn Miller?
现在是1941年
It's 1941,
伦敦闪击战还在进行
height of the London blitz,
德国轰炸战还在持续
height of the German bombing campaign.
伦敦的上空还出现了别的东西
And something else has fallen on London:
一艘设备齐全的丘拉战舰
a fully-equipped Chula warship,
世上仅此一艘 全副武装
the last one in existence, armed to the teeth.
我知道它在哪里
And I know where it is,
因为是我停的
because I parked it.
如果特工组织能出个合适的价钱
If the agency can name the right price,
我可以帮你们拿到手
I can get it for you.
不过 两小时之后
But in two hours,
德国人的炸弹会永久地摧毁它
a German bomb is going to fall on it and destroy it forever.
那就是最后期限 那就是交易
That's your deadline. That's the deal.
现在我们可以谈谈报酬吗
Now, shall we discuss payment?
你知道我在想什么吗
Do you know what I think?
什么
What?
我刚刚什么也没听进去
I think you were talking just there.
两小时之后 炸弹就会落下
Two hours, the bomb falls.
到时候就只剩尘埃和弹坑
There'll be nothing left but dust and a crater.
承诺啊 承诺
Promises, promises!
你有没有听到我说话
Are you listening to any of this?
你曾经是一位时间特工
You used to be a Time Agent,
现在是一个流浪商人
now you're some kind of freelancer.
有点刺耳啊 我倒觉得自己更像个罪犯
A little harsh! I'd like to think of myself as a criminal.
我猜也是
I bet you do.
那么 你的这个同伴是管事的吗
So this companion of yours, does he handle the business?
是呀 不过也我经常做他的代表
Well, I delegate a lot of that, yeah.
好吧 或许我们应该去找他谈
Well, maybe we should go find him.
你要怎么找
And how you gonna do that?
容易 我只要扫描一下外星科技
Easy. I'll do a scan for alien tech.
终于 这才是专业人士
Finally, a professional!
炸弹就在那块防水布下面
The bomb's under that tarpaulin.
晚上他们会把栅栏围起来
They put the fence up overnight.
看到那座医院了吗
See that building? The hospital?
怎么了
What about it?
医生就在那里
That's where the doctor is.
你应该跟他谈谈
You should talk to him.
我现在更想进到那里面去
For now, I'm more interested in getting in there.
先跟医生谈谈
Talk to the doctor first.
为什么
Why?
谈过之后你就不会想进去了
Because then maybe you won't wanna get inside.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
那房子里还有很多食物
There was a lot of food in that house.
我得让孩子们吃饱 现在应该安全了
I've got mouths to feed. Should be safe enough now.
我能问你一个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你失去了谁
Who did you lose?
什么
What?
你这么照顾那些孩子
The way you look after all those kids.
都是因为你失去了什么人 对吧
It's 'cuz you lost somebody, isn't it?
你是在弥补自己的过错
You're doing all this to make up for it.
我的弟弟
My little brother.
杰米
Jamie.
有一天晚上我出去找吃的
One night I went out looking for food.
就是那个东西落下来的那天
Same night that thing fell.
我告诉过他太危险了 不要跟着我
Told him not to follow me. I told him it was dangerous.
可是他…
But he just...
他就是不想独自一人
He just didn't like being on his own.
发生什么了
What happened?
在空袭期间 你觉得还能发生什么
In the middle of an air raid? What d'you think happened?
令人惊叹
Amazing!
惊叹什么
What is?
1941年
1941.
就在此时 离这里不远的地方
Right now, not very far from here,
德国战争机器正席卷整个欧洲
the German war machine is rolling up the map of Europe.
一个个国家就像多米诺骨牌一样倒下
Country after country, falling like dominoes.
没有人能够阻止 没有
Nothing can stop it, nothing.
直到一个多雨的小岛站出来说
Until one tiny, damp, little island says,
不 这里不行
"No! No... not here."
螳臂当车
A mouse in front of a lion.
你们太棒了 你们所有人
You're amazing, the lot of you.
不知道你们会对希特勒做什么
Dunno what you do to Hitler.
反正我是被你们吓坏了
You frighten the hell out of me!
快去吧 做你该做的事
Off you go, then. Do what you've got to do.
拯救世界
Save the world.
到处都是这些家伙
You'll find them everywhere.
每张病床上 每个病房里 成百上千
In every bed, in every ward. Hundreds of them.
我看见了
Yes, I saw.
他们为什么还戴着防毒面具
Why are they still wearing gas masks?
这不是防毒面具 你是谁
They're not. Who are you?
我是… 你就是医生吗
I'm... Are you the doctor?
我是康斯坦丁医生 你呢
Dr. Constantine. And you are?
南希让我来的
Nancy sent me.
南希
Nancy?
那你肯定问过炸弹的事了
That means you must have been asking about the bomb.
是的
Yes.
你都知道些什么
What do you know about it?
一无所知 所以才来问 你知道什么
Nothing, why I was asking. What do you know?
只知道它都做了些什么
Only what it's done.
这些人都是遭到了轰炸吗
These people,they were all caught up in the blast?
都不是
None of them were.
你病得很重
You're very sick.
我看是快病死了
Dying, I should think.
我只是一只没工夫死而已
I just haven't been able to find the time! Are you a doctor?
你是个医生吗
able to find the time! Are you a doctor?
当过一阵子
I have my moments.
你检查过他们了吗
Have you examined any of them yet?
没有
No.
别碰到皮肤
Don't touch the flesh.
哪一个
Which one?
任何一个
Any one.
你怎么看
Conclusions?
头部受了重创 主要在左侧
Massive head trauma, mostly to the left side.
部分胸腔坍缩 主要集中在右胸
Partial collapse of the chest cavity mostly to the right.
手背还有伤疤
Scarring on the back of the hand.
防毒面具似乎和皮肤焊接在一起了
The gas mask seems to be fused to the flesh
但没有灼伤的痕迹
but I can't see any burns.
检查另一个
Examine another one.
这不可能
This isn't possible.
再检查一个
And examine another.
这不可能
This isn't possible!
确实
No.
他们的伤势完全相同
They've all got the same injuries.
是的
Yes.
分毫不差
Exactly the same!
是的
Yes.
所有人一模一样
Identical, all of them.
连手背上的伤疤都一样
Right down to the scar on the back of the hand.
怎么会这样 什么时候开始的
How did this happen? How did it start?
那炸弹落下时 受害者只有一个
When that bomb dropped, there was just one victim.
死了吗
Dead?
一开始是的
At first.
他的伤情实在太严重了
His injuries were truly dreadful.
等到第二天早晨
By the following morning
所有曾经治疗过他的医生护士
every doctor and nurse who had treated him,
或者接触过他的人
who had touched him,
都出现了完全相同的伤情
had those exact same injuries.
再过一天 同一病房的所有病人
By the morning after that every patient
也都出现了完全相同的伤情
on the same ward, the exact same injuries.
不到一周就蔓延到了整个医院
Within a week, the entire hospital.
筋骨外伤 竟如瘟疫般传播
Physical injuries... as plague.
你怎么解释这个
Can you explain that?
你觉得致死原因是什么
What would you say was the cause of death?
头上的创伤
The head trauma.
不对
No.
窒息
Asphyxiation?
不对
No.
胸腔萎缩
The collapse of the chest cavity.
不对
No.
好吧
All right...
那死因是什么
what was the cause of death?
没有死因
There wasn't one.
他们没死
They're not dead.
别怕 他们不会伤人
It's all right, they're harmless.
他们就这么坐在那里
They just sort of sit there.
没有心跳 也没有任何生命体征
There's no heartbeat, no life signs of any kind.
他们就是…
They just...
不死
don't die.
那就把他们丢在这 也没人做什么吗
They're just left here? Nobody's doing anything?
我尽量让他们舒服点 我还能怎么办
I try and make them comfortable. What else is there?
只有你吗 就你一个人在这儿
Just you? You're the only one here?
大战开始前 我有子有孙
Before this war began I was a father and a grandfather.
现在我膝下空空 却还是个医生
Now I'm neither. But I'm still a doctor.
是啊 我知道你的感受
Yeah. Know the feeling.
我估计唯一的办法就是炸毁整座医院
I suspect the plan is to blow up the hospital
然后怪到德国人头上
and blame it on a German bomb.
恐怕已经来不及了
Probably too late.
我知道
I know.
现在整个伦敦…
There are isolated cases...
整个伦敦…都有…零星病例
isolated cases breaking out... all over... London.
退后 别靠近
Stay back! Stay back!
听好
Listen to me!
顶层 802房间
Top floor, Room 802.
那里就是第一个受害者
That's where they took the first victim,
住院的房间
the one from the crash site.
还有 你必须再找到南希
And you must find Nancy again.
南希
Nancy?
受害者是她弟弟
It was her brother.
她没有说出全部真相
She knows more than she's saying.
她不肯告诉我 但她…
She won't tell me, but she m...
妈…咪…
Mum meee...
你…是不是
are... you...
我的…妈咪
my... Mummy?
有人吗
Hello?
晚上好 希望没有打扰到您
Good evening. Hope we're not interrupting.
在下杰克·哈克尼斯
Jack Harkness.
我这一路上听说了不少你的事迹
I've been hearing all about you on the way over.
他知道 我必须告诉他 我们时间特工的身份
He knows. I had to tell him. About us being Time Agents.
非常荣幸见到您 史波克先生
And it's a real pleasure to meet you, Mr Spock.
史波克先生
Mr Spock?
不然我该怎么说
What was I supposed to say?
你连个名字都没有
You don't have a name.
你从没厌倦过"博士"的称呼吗
Don't you ever get tired of "Doctor"
神秘博士
Dr who?
叫了九百年 我习惯了
Nine centuries in, I'm coping.
你干什么去了 现在正是伦敦大轰炸
Where have you been? We are in the middle of London Blitz.
可不是到处乱逛的好时候
It's not a good time for a stroll!
我可没乱逛 我坐防空气球去了
Who's strollin'? I went by barrage balloon.
那可是观赏大空袭的好地方
Only way to see an air raid.
什么
What?
我问你 什么是丘拉战舰
Listen, what's a Chula warship?
丘拉
Chula?
求你了 妈咪 让我进去
Please, Mummy. Please let me in.
我害怕炸弹 妈咪
I'm scared of the bombs, Mummy.
妈咪
Mummy?
Mummy!
妈咪
这根本不可能啊 怎么会这样
This just isn't possible. How did this happen?
那艘丘拉飞船是什么样的
What kind of Chula ship landed here?
什么
What?
他说那是艘战舰
He said it was a warship.
他偷走了 藏起来了
He stole it, parked it somewhere,
没多久就会被炸弹炸到
somewhere a bomb's gonna to fall on it.
除非我们开个价买下来
Unless we make him an offer.
什么样的战舰
What kind of warship?
有关系吗
Does it matter?
跟这个毫不相干
It's got nothing to do with this.
这个怪病就是从爆炸地点传开的
This started at the bomb site.
关系大了
It's got everything to do with it.
什么样的战舰
What kind of warship?
一艘医疗船
An ambulance!
你看 你们在时间漩涡中追逐的就是这个
Look, this is what chased you through the time vortex.
就是块太空垃圾 我想骗你说很值钱
It's space junk. I wanted to kid you it was valuable.
是空的 我查过了 只剩一个空壳
It's empty. I made sure of it. Nothing but a shell.
是我把它扔向你们
I threw it at you,
我看见了你们的时间机器
saw your time-travel vehicle
另外说一句 外表我喜欢
love the retro look, by the way, nice panels.
引你们上钩
Threw you the bait...
上钩
Bait?
我想把这玩意卖给你们
I wanted to sell it to you,
然后趁你们发现它毫无价值之前毁掉它
then destroy it before you found out it was junk.
你跟我说这是战舰
You said it was a warship.
战场上总有医疗船吧
They have ambulances in wars.
这是个骗局 我骗了你们
It's a con. I was conning you.
这才是我的真面目 一个骗子
That's what I am, I'm a con man!
还以为你们是时间特工 其实不是对吧
Thought you were Time Agents. You're not,are you?
两个流浪者而已
Just a couple more freelancers.
我早该看出来的
I should've known,
你看你们俩都是怎么融入时代的
the way you guys are blending with the local colour!
国旗女就够糟的了 你还史波克船长
Flag Girl was bad enough, but U-Boat Captain? !
总之 发生在这里的事
Anyway, whatever's happening here
跟那艘船一点关系都没有
has got nothing to do with that ship.
到底是什么情况 博士
What IS happening here, Doctor?
人类DNA被改写了
Human DNA is being rewritten.
被一个白痴改的
By an idiot.
什么意思
What do you mean?
不知道 某种病毒似的东西
I don't know, some kind of virus
把人类转化成这个样子 但是为什么呢
converting human beings into these things. But why?
有什么意义
What's the point?
妈咪
Mummy?
妈咪你在哪
Where's my mummy?
妈咪
Mum-my!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mummy! Mum-my! Mummy?
怎么回事
What's happening?
我不知道
I don't know.
妈咪
Mummy?
是我 南希
It's me - Nancy!
别被他们碰到
Don't let 'em touch you!
被他们碰到了会怎样
What happens if they touch us?
下场就在你眼前
You're looking at it!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
我是南希 你姐姐
It's Nancy, your sister.
你死了 杰米 你已经死了
You're dead, Jamie. You're dead.
妈咪 妈咪
Mum-my! Mum-my!
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mum-my! Mummy! Mum-my!
下集预告
我不知道这是怎么回事 但请相信我
I don't know what's happening here, but Believe me,
跟我没有半点关系
I'd nothing to do with it!
我告诉你是怎么回事
I'll tell you what's happening,
你忘了上闹钟了
you forgot to set your alarm clock.
今天是火山爆发之日
It's Volcano Day!
那道门应该能撑一阵子
That door should hold it for a bit.
那道门 连墙都没阻止他们
The door? ! The wall didn't stop it!
站住不许动
Halt! Don't move!
来吧 问我问题 我正在兴头上呢
Go on ask me anything, I'm on fire!
你有两下子 那就露两手吧
You've got the moves, show me your moves.
博士跳个舞又不会造成世界末日
The world doesn't end cos The Doctor dances.
退后
Stay back!
妈咪
Mummy!
博士
Doctor!
把那道门封住
Secure those gates!
为什么 -快去
Why? - Just do it!
那么厉害的武器全都在这个
All that weapons tech in the hands of
一直在找妈妈的四岁小孩手中
a hysteric four-year-old looking for his mummy
没有什么能阻止他了
and nothing in the world can stop it!